Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Hi guys.
大家好。
My name is Katherine and today we have an upper intermediate level lesson for you about
我是Katherine，今天我们要为大家带来一节中高级课程，内容是关于
some very interesting things.
一些非常有趣的事情。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about fortune tellers or people that read your future.
今天我们要聊聊算命师，或者那些能预知你未来的人。
Alright so if I want to know who I will marry, if I will be rich, I will go to this fortune
好的，如果我想知道我会嫁给谁，会不会变有钱，我就会去找这个算命师，
teller and she or he will tell me what's in my future.
他或她会告诉我未来会发生什么。
That's right.
没错。
It's very popular in many cultures around the world, many different ways of reading
这在世界各地的许多文化中都很流行，有很多不同的方式来解读
your future or telling you your future.
你的未来或告诉你你的未来。
So let's jump into this dialogue and see what's going on today.
那我们就进入今天的对话，看看发生了什么。
Look at this newspaper article about this famous local medium.
看看这篇关于当地著名灵媒的报纸文章。
It says that she is really gifted and so popular now that she's booked solid with appointments
上面说她真的很有天赋，现在非常受欢迎，预约已经排满了
for the next 12 months.
未来12个月。
You don't really believe in all that hocus pocus mumbo jumbo do you?
你不会真的相信那些花招和胡言乱语吧？
Well I have had many friends that went to a psychic and got their palms read and most
嗯，我有很多朋友去找过通灵师，让他们看手相，而且
of the things the psychic told them came true.
通灵师告诉他们的大部分事情都应验了。
Of course it does.
当然会应验。
They tell you general and obvious things like that you'll be successful or have a big house.
他们告诉你一些笼统又显而易见的事情，比如你会成功或者会有大房子。
I think most of the times they're just scam artists.
我觉得他们大多数时候就是些骗子。
Well historically it's a practice that many cultures share.
嗯，从历史上看，这是许多文化共有的习俗。
Reading the tarot cards.
解读塔罗牌。
In the east they would even read tea leaves.
在东方，他们甚至会看茶叶渣。
I even heard that there are people that make you smoke a cigar and then read your ashes.
我甚至听说有人会让你抽雪茄，然后解读你的烟灰。
All superstitious nonsense.
全是迷信的胡说八道。
I would still like to go to one and see what he or she has to say just for kicks.
我还是想去见一个，听听他或她会说什么，就图个乐子。
Great.
太好了。
I'll make an appointment.
我来预约。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So a lot of interesting things here.
这里有很多有趣的东西。
Let's take a look at some of those words on Language Takeaway.
我们来看看“语言要点”中的一些单词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So in Language Takeaway today we are focusing on some words that describe fortune telling
在今天的“语言要点”中，我们重点讲一些描述算命
but also the different ways of doing so.
以及不同算命方式的词。
The first word we have is actually a name for a person who can read the future.
第一个词实际上是指能预知未来的人。
Right Marco?
对吧，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
A medium.
灵媒。
In the dialogue we hear about a woman who is a medium and is very talented.
在对话中，我们听说一个女人是灵媒，而且非常有天赋。
Actually a medium is interesting because a medium is a person who can communicate with
实际上，灵媒很有趣，因为灵媒是能与
the dead.
死者沟通的人。
That's right.
没错。
Or who can communicate with the other side.
或者能与另一个世界沟通。
But if you think about middle, medium, I mean they mean the same thing.
但如果你想想“中间”、“媒介”，我的意思是它们意思相同。
It's someone who is in the middle of two things.
就是处于两者之间的人。
And so a medium can maybe transmit these different ideas or signals.
所以灵媒可能能传递这些不同的想法或信号。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's a person that basically communicates as you say with the dead or someone that can
所以基本上就是像你说的那样，与死者沟通的人，或者能
listen to people who are not here anymore.
倾听那些已不在人世的人的人。
But obviously they are a type of person that could also use this gift to tell your future
但显然，他们也是那种能利用这种天赋来告诉你未来
or to have the people who are dead tell you what's going to happen in the future.
或者让死者告诉你未来会发生什么的人。
That's right.
没错。
And so another kind of person who would do something similar is a psychic.
另一种做类似事情的人是通灵师。
That's right.
没错。
Alright now a psychic is a person who generally will read your future for you, will tell you
好的，通灵师通常是指会为你解读未来、告诉你
the future.
未来的人。
Maybe the psychic will have a special tool like a crystal ball.
也许通灵师会有特殊的工具，比如水晶球。
Just remember that in English, psych, like psychology, psychosis has to do with your
请记住，在英语中，“psych”就像“psychology”（心理学）、“psychosis”（精神病）一样，与你的
mind.
心智有关。
Alright.
好的。
So a psychic uses their mind to find out things about you or your future.
所以通灵师用心智来发现关于你或你未来的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So sometimes psychics will claim that they can read your mind as well.
所以有时通灵师也会声称他们能读懂你的心思。
Right.
对。
It's a little scary.
有点吓人。
So as you say, these are different, these are people who supposedly can tell you your
所以就像你说的，这些是不同的，这些人据称能告诉你你的
future.
未来。
And as you said, they use different methods or different tools.
而且正如你所说，他们使用不同的方法或不同的工具。
One of them is for example having your palms read.
其中之一就是看手相。
Alright, so the psychic will go to you Marco and will look at your hand and will read your
好的，所以通灵师会走到你面前，Marco，看着你的手，然后解读你的
palm.
手掌。
Now where on your hand is your palm?
你手上的手掌在哪里？
It's on the other side, the side where you grab things with.
在另一面，就是你抓东西的那一面。
The inside, so the soft part.
里面，就是柔软的部分。
And maybe on your palm you have many different lines.
也许你的手掌上有很多不同的纹路。
So the psychic will look at the lines and will say, oh well this line is very long,
所以灵媒会看着掌纹说，哦，这条线很长，
so you will have a long, long life.
所以你会很长寿。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe in your hands you have lines that determine how much money you will have or
所以也许你手上的掌纹能决定你会有多少钱，
how many kids you will have or how long you will live.
或者会有几个孩子，或者能活多久。
So that's called a palm reading.
这就叫看手相。
Or I am going to have my palm read.
或者我要去算个手相。
That's right.
没错。
Now the other person doesn't really believe in all that stuff and says that they are just
而另一个人并不相信这些东西，说他们只是
scam artists.
骗子。
So he's saying that the psychics or the mediums are just scam artists.
所以他说那些灵媒或通灵者只是骗子。
Alright, so what is a scam artist?
好的，那什么是骗子？
Well a scam artist is not a real artist.
嗯，骗子可不是真正的艺术家。
A scam artist is a thief, someone who will maybe tell you a story or who will lie to
骗子是小偷，是那种可能会给你编个故事或撒谎
you to try and take your money.
来骗你钱的人。
That's right.
没错。
So he's not really like a robber, like somebody that will break into your house and take your
所以他不是那种强盗，比如闯进你家拿走你
things.
东西的人。
No, he won't use a gun, maybe, hopefully not, but he will tell you a story or will lie to
不，他不会用枪，也许希望不会，但他会给你编个故事或撒谎，
you in a way that makes you want to give him money.
用一种让你心甘情愿给他钱的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So I don't know if any of you have ever received an email from someone who said, I am a wealthy
所以我不知道你们有没有收到过这样的邮件，有人说，我是来自世界另一端的富人，
person from a different part of the world and I want you to give me money to help me
我想让你给我钱帮我，
so I can come to America and these kinds of things where you don't know the person, he's
这样我就能来美国之类的事情，你根本不认识这个人，他
probably lying to you, it's a very sad story.
可能在骗你，故事很悲惨。
I say please give me money so I can come to visit you or so I can come and have a good
我说请给我钱，这样我就能来看你，或者这样我就能过上
life.
好日子。
That's a scam artist.
那就是骗子。
That's right.
没错。
People probably don't have a bad life, they just want you to give them money.
那些人可能生活并不糟糕，他们只是想要你给钱。
That's right.
没错。
So that is a scam artist.
所以那就是骗子。
And well he went on to say about how all of these things, about fortune telling, about
然后他接着说，所有这些事情，比如算命、
psychics and everything is just superstitious nonsense.
灵媒之类的，都只是迷信的胡说八道。
So then the girl went on to explain and saying that it's not really true that many cultures
然后女孩接着解释说，其实并不完全是这样，很多文化
do things like, for example, read the tarot cards.
都会做类似的事情，比如读塔罗牌。
Alright so we had palm reading first, maybe talking to dead people with a medium.
好的，我们之前说了看手相，也许还有通过灵媒和死人说话。
But this is another tool that psychics use to communicate with maybe the dead or to understand
但这是灵媒用来与死者沟通或了解
the future.
未来的另一种工具。
So we have tarot cards and they're actually cards, like playing cards, but they're a little
所以有塔罗牌，它们其实是牌，像扑克牌，但有点
bit different, right?
不同，对吧？
They don't have diamonds and hearts, they have different pictures.
它们没有方块和红心，而是有不同的图案。
Right, they have pictures of, for example, a king or a queen or a picture of a river
对，它们有图案，比如国王或王后，或者河流的图片，
or different symbols that basically the person who is getting their fortune read will take
或者不同的符号，基本上，被算命的人会
it and move them and shuffle them and then will start flipping the cards over and then
拿起它们，洗牌，然后开始翻牌，
you will see supposedly what your future will be like.
然后你就能看到据说你的未来会是什么样子。
Alright so those are tarot cards.
好的，那就是塔罗牌。
But we have one more word here and it actually comes from the friend who doesn't believe
但我们这里还有一个词，它实际上来自那个不相信
in these scam artists.
这些骗子的朋友。
It calls it all superstitious nonsense.
他把这称为迷信的胡说八道。
That's right.
没错。
So a person that is superstitious believes in superstitions and those are beliefs of
所以迷信的人相信迷信，那些是关于
good or bad luck.
好运或坏运的信念。
Yeah that's right.
是的，没错。
So if I believe that the number 13 is very very bad, I will avoid the number 13.
所以如果我相信数字13非常非常不吉利，我会避开数字13。
I won't sit down in chair number 13, I won't buy a house on floor number 13 because I'm
我不会坐在13号椅子上，我不会买13楼的房子，因为我
superstitious.
迷信。
I believe that that number is bad luck.
我相信那个数字会带来坏运。
That's right.
没错。
So many believe that it's bad luck to break a mirror or to walk under a ladder.
所以很多人相信打碎镜子或从梯子下走过会带来坏运。
Yes, also many Americans believe it's bad luck to open an umbrella inside.
是的，很多美国人也相信在室内打开雨伞会带来坏运。
That's right.
没错。
So it's interesting because many cultures around the world have different types of superstitions
所以这很有趣，因为世界各地的许多文化都有不同类型的迷信，
but we'll talk about that in a little bit.
但我们稍后会讨论这个。
Why don't we move on now to some fluency builder and take a look at some phrases.
我们现在不如继续看一些流利度练习，看看一些短语。
Look at this newspaper article about this famous local medium.
看看这篇关于这位著名本地灵媒的报纸文章。
It says that she is really gifted and so popular now that she's booked solid with appointments
上面说她真的很有天赋，现在非常受欢迎，预约已经排满了
for the next 12 months.
未来12个月。
You don't really believe in all that hocus pocus mumbo jumbo do you?
你不会真的相信那些骗人的鬼把戏吧？
Well I have had many friends that went to a psychic and got their palms read and most
嗯，我有许多朋友去过灵媒那里看手相，而且灵媒告诉他们的
of the things the psychic told them came true.
大部分事情都应验了。
Of course it does.
当然会应验。
They tell you general and obvious things like that you'll be successful or have a big house.
他们告诉你一些笼统而明显的事情，比如你会成功或有大房子。
I think most of the times they're just scam artists.
我觉得大多数时候他们只是骗子。
Well historically it's a practice that many cultures share.
嗯，从历史上看，这是许多文化共有的做法。
Reading the tarot cards.
读塔罗牌。
In the east they would even read tea leaves.
在东方，他们甚至会看茶叶渣。
I even heard that there are people that make you smoke a cigar and then read your ashes.
我甚至听说有人让你抽雪茄，然后看你的烟灰。
All superstitious nonsense.
全是迷信的胡说八道。
I would still like to go to one and see what he or she has to say just for kicks.
我还是想去算一次命，听听他或她会说些什么，纯粹为了好玩。
Great.
太好了。
I'll book an appointment.
我会预约一个时间。
Alright.
好的。
An important phrase that you don't have to be a psychic to use is booked solid.
一个重要的短语，你不需要是通灵者也能用，那就是“booked solid”（预订满了）。
Now we heard this in the beginning of the dialogue.
现在我们来听听对话开头的那部分。
Right because this person is so famous that so many people want to go there and get their
对，因为这个人太有名了，所以很多人都想去那里找他。
fortunes read that this person is already booked solid for the next 12 months.
算命显示，这个人未来12个月的档期已经排满了。
Okay now booked solid is a very nice colloquial way to describe having no time for anything
好的，"booked solid" 是一种非常口语化的说法，用来形容忙得一点时间都没有。
in English.
用英语说。
So basically if a restaurant for example is booked solid it means there are no tables
所以基本上，如果一家餐厅被订满了，意思就是没有空桌了。
available.
可用的。
That's right.
没错。
Nothing is available.
什么都没有。
Everything is already reserved.
一切都已经预订好了。
Yeah it happens also with hotels.
是的，酒店也会这样。
Some hotels during let's say the Olympics many of them are booked solid for the entire
有些酒店，比如在奥运会期间，很多都被预订满了，整个期间都没有空房。
month.
一个月。
Or you could even say this with your friends.
或者你也可以跟朋友这么说。
You say hey Marco do you want to hang out Thursday say 7 o'clock.
你说：“嘿，Marco，周四晚上7点你想出来玩吗？”
Sorry I'm booked solid the entire day.
抱歉，我今天一整天都排满了。
Popular guy.
大忙人啊。
That's right.
没错。
So you can say that a person is booked solid or that a business is booked solid.
所以你可以说一个人“booked solid”，或者一家公司“booked solid”。
Now this next phrase is kind of more it's not really real words but we say they are
下一个短语有点像是，不是真正的词，但我们说它们是
hocus pocus mumbo jumbo.
胡言乱语、鬼把戏。
Alright hocus pocus is a way to describe superstitious things.
好吧，“hocus pocus”是用来描述迷信事物的方式。
Like magic right because I think it comes from supposedly it's a spell that witches
就像魔法一样，对吧？因为我觉得它来自据说女巫
or wizards will say like hocus pocus and things will appear.
或巫师会念的咒语，比如“hocus pocus”，然后东西就会出现。
Abracadabra.
阿布拉卡达布拉。
Hocus yeah.
对，hocus。
But basically this is something that we say when we're joking now in English.
但基本上，这是现在英语中我们开玩笑时说的话。
So I'll say oh gosh Marco I just broke this mirror.
所以我会说，哦天哪，Marco，我刚打碎了这面镜子。
Seven years bad luck.
七年厄运。
Do you really believe in all that hocus pocus?
你真的相信那些鬼把戏吗？
Yes I'm very superstitious.
是的，我非常迷信。
So hocus pocus here means superstitious.
所以这里的“hocus pocus”意思是迷信。
Like magic superstitious stuff.
就像魔法、迷信的东西。
It's all hocus pocus.
全是鬼把戏。
What about mumbo jumbo?
那“mumbo jumbo”呢？
Mumbo jumbo is also something we say when we're talking about magic or things that are
Mumbo jumbo 也是我们在谈论魔法或迷信事物时说的一个词。
superstitious.
迷信的。
So I can say I don't believe in any of that superstitious mumbo jumbo.
所以我可以说不相信任何那种迷信的胡言乱语。
It means basically I don't trust it.
它基本上意味着我不信任它。
I don't think it's true.
我不认为它是真的。
I think it's silly.
我觉得它很傻。
Right so mumbo jumbo you refer to that nonsense that irrational or unbelievable stuff.
对，所以 mumbo jumbo 指的是那些胡说八道、不合理或不可信的东西。
That's right it's irrational.
没错，它是不合理的。
Very good.
很好。
So hocus referring to magic mumbo jumbo referring to superstition or things that are not really
所以 hocus 指的是魔法，mumbo jumbo 指的是迷信或不太可信的东西，可以这么说。
believable let's say.
不太可信的。
And to end the dialogue the guy says well you know what okay let's go to this psychic
对话结尾，那个家伙说：你知道吗，好吧，我们去找这个灵媒，听听她怎么说，就图个乐子。
and see what she has to say just for kicks.
就图个乐子。
Just for kicks.
Now I love this phrase.
我很喜欢这个短语。
I use it a lot.
我经常用它。
It's very very colloquial very spoken English so you guys should try to use it.
它非常口语化，是很地道的英语口语，所以你们应该试着用一下。
It means just for fun.
它的意思就是“只是为了好玩”。
Just for fun.
只是为了好玩。
So I'm not going because I believe.
所以我去不是因为我相信。
Right.
没错。
Because I just said I think it's hocus pocus mumbo jumbo.
因为我刚说我觉得这是骗人的鬼话。
But I do think it will be fun.
但我确实觉得会很有趣。
So let's go just for kicks.
所以我们就去玩玩吧。
Just for kicks.
就为了好玩。
Yeah.
嗯。
So it means that you're doing something not seriously.
所以它的意思是，你做某事不是认真的。
You're just doing it for fun.
你只是为了好玩才做。
That's right.
对。
So you can do anything just for kicks really.
所以你真的可以为了好玩做任何事。
Maybe like if you just sit down and start doing some math problems just for kicks.
比如，你坐下来开始做数学题，只是为了好玩。
Yeah you would do that wouldn't you Marco?
嗯，你会那样做，对吧，马可？
Just for kicks.
就为了好玩。
Yeah.
嗯。
Or I'm going to take a singing class just for kicks even though I don't take singing
或者我要去上唱歌课，只是为了好玩，尽管我并不是很认真对待唱歌这件事。
very seriously.
很认真。
Right.
没错。
It's not like you want to become a professional singer.
并不是你想成为专业歌手。
You just want to do it for fun.
你只是想找点乐子。
That's right.
对。
All right.
好吧。
Great stuff.
太棒了。
Why don't we review everything one last time.
我们最后再复习一遍吧。
Look at this newspaper article about this famous local medium.
看看这篇关于当地著名灵媒的报纸文章。
It says that she is really gifted and so popular now that she's booked solid with appointments
文章说她真的很有天赋，现在非常受欢迎，预约已经排满了，
for the next 12 months.
未来12个月都满了。
You don't really believe in all that hocus pocus mumbo jumbo do you?
你不会真的相信那些骗人的鬼把戏吧？
Well I have had many friends that went to a psychic and got their palms read and most
嗯，我有很多朋友去找过灵媒看手相，而且灵媒告诉他们的
of the things the psychic told them came true.
大部分事情都应验了。
Of course it does.
当然会应验了。
They tell you general and obvious things like that you'll be successful or have a big house.
他们只会告诉你一些笼统又显而易见的事，比如你会成功，或者会住大房子。
I think most of the times they're just scam artists.
我觉得他们大多数时候就是骗子。
Well historically it's a practice that many cultures share.
嗯，从历史上看，这是一种许多文化都共有的做法。
Reading the tarot cards.
比如解读塔罗牌。
In the east they would even read tea leaves.
在东方，他们甚至会看茶叶渣。
I even heard that there are people that make you smoke a cigar and then read your ashes.
我甚至听说有人让你抽雪茄，然后看你的烟灰来算命。
All superstitious nonsense.
全是迷信的胡说八道。
I would still like to go to one and see what he or she has to say just for kicks.
我还是想去见一个灵媒，听听他或她会说什么，就图个乐子。
Great.
好啊。
I'll make an appointment.
我来预约。
All right.
好吧。
So speaking about superstitions as you said some superstitions are more local.
说到迷信，就像你说的，有些迷信更具地方特色。
Like for example I think it's Americans that believe it's bad luck to open an umbrella
比如，我觉得是美国人相信在室内打开雨伞
inside a house.
会带来厄运。
I know that for example in China it's the number four is considered bad luck.
我知道，比如在中国，数字四被认为是不吉利的。
That's right.
没错。
So you'll see that many buildings don't have a floor number four or 14.
所以你会看到很多建筑没有四楼或十四楼。
That's right.
没错。
And actually it's similar in Western cultures because some hotels will not have a floor
实际上，在西方文化中也有类似的情况，因为有些酒店没有
13.
13楼。
That's right.
没错。
Are there any superstitions that are from Ecuador?
厄瓜多尔有什么迷信吗？
I think Hispanic.
我觉得是西班牙裔的。
There is one that's very particular with women with Hispanic women.
有一个非常特别的，关于西班牙裔女性的。
They will not put their bags, their purses on the floor.
她们不会把包或手提包放在地上。
Yes.
是的。
I've heard this before.
我以前听说过这个。
What is it?
是什么原因？
Your money will fly away.
你的钱会飞走。
Your money will fall out or your money will go away.
你的钱会掉出来，或者你的钱会没了。
So women will not put their bags or their purses on the floor.
所以女性不会把包或手提包放在地上。
That's why you will always put it on a chair or on the table.
这就是为什么她们总是把包放在椅子或桌子上。
Never never on the floor.
绝对绝对不能放在地上。
They're very superstitious about this.
她们对此非常迷信。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
Well have you ever had your fortune told by a psychic?
嗯，你曾经让灵媒给你算过命吗？
No.
没有。
I've never.
我从来没有。
I've seen gypsies.
我见过吉普赛人。
So gypsies are people that don't really live somewhere.
吉普赛人就是那些不真正定居在某处的人。
They don't settle anywhere.
他们不在任何地方安家。
They move around.
他们到处游走。
They go from city to city.
他们从一个城市到另一个城市。
And I've seen them and they've approached me asking me if I want my fortune read.
我见过他们，他们曾走近我，问我要不要算命。
But I don't really believe in that.
但我并不真的相信那个。
So it just seems like they wanted me to give them $5 and they would just tell me anything.
所以感觉他们就是想让我给他们五美元，然后随便说点什么。
You think it was mumbo jumbo?
你觉得那是胡说八道吗？
I think it was mumbo jumbo.
我觉得那是胡说八道。
Have you had your fortune read?
你算过命吗？
I've had tarot cards read for me.
有人给我算过塔罗牌。
To be honest I don't really remember what my fortune was.
说实话，我不太记得我的命运是什么了。
I don't remember if it was right or not right.
我不记得它准不准了。
But I do remember feeling very uncomfortable because the things that my... and I don't
但我确实记得当时感觉很不舒服，因为那些……而且我
believe in these things because I'm not superstitious.
并不相信这些东西，因为我不迷信。
But the things that the fortune teller told me I thought were interesting because they
但算命先生告诉我的事情，我觉得很有趣，因为它们
were very similar to things that I knew about myself.
和我对自己的了解非常相似。
So I don't know.
所以，我也不确定。
Some people... it's interesting because some people will go to a fortune teller just for
有些人……有趣的是，有些人去找算命先生只是为了
kicks and will actually agree or find it amazing what the fortune teller told them.
好玩，而且实际上会认同算命先生告诉他们的，或者觉得那很神奇。
And other people aren't really just not really interested.
而另一些人则真的不太感兴趣。
But it's very, very... it's very closely related to different cultures.
但这非常、非常……它与不同的文化紧密相关。
Some people have witch doctors that also will cleanse you or tell you your future and stuff
有些人有巫医，他们也会为你净化，或者告诉你未来之类的
like that.
事情。
That's right.
没错。
So we're actually very curious to hear about your culture.
所以我们真的很好奇想听听你们的文化。
Do you have superstitions in your culture and are there traditional forms of fortune
你们的文化中有迷信吗？有没有传统的算命
telling?
方式？
Let us know, our website is EnglishPod.com.
告诉我们吧，我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right guys, we'll see you there.
好了，各位，我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。